Enis Davud

(845) 863-7523 | enisdavud@gmail.com | Newburgh, NY https://www.linkedin.com/in/enis-davud-b91741b7/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Detail-oriented problem solver with 460+ training hours and experience developing full-stack Java applications. Interested in attaining a career that will allow me the opportunity to excel in software development as well as highlight my previous work experience and leadership abilities.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

W3Schools JavaScript Certification (in progress; expected date of completion 12/2022)

- Java
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- Spring Boot

- Spring Data JPA
- Spring Security (JWT)
- Bootstrap
- REST API's
- SQL

- Unit Testing (JUnit, Mockito)
- SOLID OOP Principles
- Dependencies Injection
- Git

EXPERIENCE

Generation Junior Full Stack Java Developer Program | August 2022 - December 2022 *Training Participant (in progress)*

- aining Participant (in progress)
 - Participating in a 16-week, 460+ hour Junior Full Stack Java Developer program that emphasizes hands-on practical application.
 - Learning and deploying the technologies involved in creating full-stack web applications with Java using Spring Boot Framework, JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3.
 - Implementing basic unit tests and deploying the application to Heroku.

Self-Employed | Newburgh, NY | February 2021 - Present

Private Chemistry & Biology Tutor

- Provide one-on-one academic assistance for students at local high schools, community colleges, and universities across the country, including Ivy League such as Columbia University.
- Manage relationships with students and parents to communicate feedback and future progression.

Newburgh Enlarged City School District | Newburgh, NY | March 2021 - June 2022

Leave-Replacement Substitute Teacher

- Formulated lesson plans & instructed lessons in Biology, Forensic Science, and Anatomy & Physiology to high school students with clear and effective communication.
- Coordinated with administration and teachers to discuss class status and progress.

EDUCATION

University at Albany, SUNY - Class of 2020

Bachelor of Science in Human Biology